<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Smart Sprout Content Services | Web Design | SEO on SmartSprout Content Marketing</title>
    <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Smart Sprout Content Services | Web Design | SEO on SmartSprout Content Marketing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smartsprout.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The secret to high ranking posts on Google</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/the-secret-to-high-ranking-posts-on-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/the-secret-to-high-ranking-posts-on-google/</guid>
      <description>You may be aware that content marketing can bring targeted traffic to your website. However, you might be wondering, if there is already so much content on the internet, how do you stand out and rank on the first page of Google? In this post, I will share my secrets on how to make your mark in a crowded marketplace.
Focus not on each post This may sound counter-intuitive, but this one thing, done well, will put you head and shoulders above your competitors on Google search and deliver return visitors in the masses (which is where the conversions happen).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to decrease loading time</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/how-to-decrease-loading-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/how-to-decrease-loading-time/</guid>
      <description>Page loading speed is not just important for improving the user-experience. In fact, page loading time affects visitor retention, sales conversions, and even search rankings. This is how we recommend speeding up your website:
Resize and optimise images If your website is slow, your image file size could be to blame. Before using an image, at the very least it should be resized to match the maximum display dimensions and compressed using image compression tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to properly attribute images on your blog</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/properly-attribute-images-on-your-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 05:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/properly-attribute-images-on-your-blog/</guid>
      <description>While image attribution isn&amp;rsquo;t always required, there are instances when the best image for the job requires attribution (by law). This short guide explains where to find blog images, which images need attributing and how to attribute your images correctly.
Which images require attribution? Some websites, such as Unsplash and Pixabay have a sizeable library of images that have been marked as needing no attribution, but there are other sites (such as Flickr and Wikimedia Commons) where some images are offered free of charge in return for attribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is content marketing?</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/what-is-content-marketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 02:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/what-is-content-marketing/</guid>
      <description>Though many companies are employing content marketing as part of their overall marketing strategy, a large portion of marketers admit that they don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand it. Below, we take a look at the definition of content marketing and how your business may benefit.
 &amp;ldquo;Content is where I expect much of the real money will be made on the Internet, just as it was in broadcasting&amp;rdquo; — Bill Gates, 1996</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write blog posts quickly</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/how-to-write-blog-posts-quickly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 19:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/how-to-write-blog-posts-quickly/</guid>
      <description>#1 Know your topic! While you can&amp;rsquo;t always be an expert in every subject you tackle, make sure you know your stuff before you put pen to paper. Only then, will you know how to correctly structure the piece and write an article that will wow your readership.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know your subject inside out, aim to speak to someone who does. Arrange an interview and prepare a set of questions, leaving time for your expert to school you on some things that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know to ask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy &amp; Cookie Policy</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 01:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This website has been provided for information pertaining to Smart Sprout and our services. The below information sets out how Smart Sprout uses and protects the data collected via our website.
When using this site, you are legally bound to the following privacy policy, so please read carefully. Privacy protection is something that Smart Sprout are fully committed towards and we thoroughly support the implementation of the GDPR as we feel that it important for people to be able to understand and control their own data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which voice is right for my business blog?</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/which-voice-is-right-for-my-business-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 15:55:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/which-voice-is-right-for-my-business-blog/</guid>
      <description>Should your blog be written in the first person? For brands like Nike and Apple, their products are endorsed by influential people and are promoted at high-profile sporting events and on prime-time television. Thus, many of their customers are arguably using their products as an extension of their own persona/image.
As these brands are designed to make their users feel powerful/elite, a corporate, authoritative voice is most suited here.
When choosing whether to use the first person in your business blog, consider the following questions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to optimise images for your website</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/how-to-prepare-images-for-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 02:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/how-to-prepare-images-for-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Have you heard about image optimisation, but you don&amp;rsquo;t know how to do it or what image optimisation does for your website? If so, you are in for a treat! Below, I will take you through everything you need to know to optimise the images on your website, boosting performance instantly!
What is image optimisation? Image optimisation is the process of reducing the file size of your images with minimal visual quality loss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use your blog to gather leads</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/how-to-use-your-blog-to-gather-leads/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/how-to-use-your-blog-to-gather-leads/</guid>
      <description>Your blog is a powerful lead generation tool if you know how to use it. While a blog is never a tool for passive income, it is, potentially, very cost effective in comparison to other tools available, such as paid advertising.
Build a business blog that delivers! Before your blog can generate leads, it needs to meet several criteria:
Posts should be:
 part of a detailed content strategy in line with the needs or desires of your target market significantly better than other content in your niche written accurately (both in their content and grammar)  In addition, you will need to post frequently to keep the interest of your users (this also helps with search engine rankings); but how frequently is frequently?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What should business bloggers write about?</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/what-should-business-bloggers-write-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 23:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/blog/what-should-business-bloggers-write-about/</guid>
      <description>Know your customers Before you start blogging, you must know who you are blogging for. Take some time to think about your customer/client base and consider what these people have in common. Ask yourself, what common issues do my customers face and which of these issues can I help to solve?
With their common interest or problem in mind, make a list of questions your customers/clients might ask and categorise them into groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/about/</guid>
      <description>About Smart Sprout Smart Sprout is a digital content agency like no other. Unlike other digital and content marketing agencies, we don&amp;rsquo;t focus on cheap labour. Instead, each of our team members is an expert in their field with a demonstrable track record.
In fact, every member of the team was headhunted for their specific skill set, and we are proud of it!
Another thing that makes Smart Sprout different to other agencies is our flexibility and range of content services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/examples/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smartsprout.netlify.app/team/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
